theboxtrolls.com 2019-11-01

# Privacy Policy

Updated 06 September, 2019.  

This Privacy Policy applies to our websites located at www.laika.com, www.coraline.com, www.paranorman.com and www.theboxtrolls.com (collectively referred to herein as "the Site") and all features, content, and other services that we own, control and make available through such service locations that link to this Privacy Policy (collectively, the “Service”). The Site and Service are owned, operated, licensed or controlled by LAIKA, LLC ("LAIKA", “WE” or “US”). We know that you care about how information about you is used and shared, and your privacy is of the utmost importance to LAIKA. We promise that we will use information about you carefully and sensibly. This Privacy Policy describes the information that we collect about visitors to our Site, how we use that information and how we protect that information. It also discusses certain choices you have regarding your personal information. This Privacy Policy applies only to information collected through the Service and does not apply to information collected by LAIKA through any other means. 

BY USING THE SERVICE, YOU CONSENT TO THE TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND TO OUR PROCESSING OF PERSONAL INFORMATION FOR THE PURPOSES STATED BELOW AND YOU AGREE TO OUR TERMS OF USE. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THE TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY OR THE TERMS OF USE, PLEASE DO NOT USE THE SERVICE. 

**PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT  **

**Automatically Generated Information.** Whenever you visit the Site or access or use the Service, we receive and store information about that visit. For example, we obtain information about you and your Web browser (collectively, “Usage Information”), including: 

  * The Internet Protocol (IP) address that connects your computer to the Internet; 
  * Your email address and confirmation when you open an email sent from the Site; 
  * Your user name(s) and password(s); 
  * Your browser type and version, device identifier, operating system and platform, and other computer and connection information; 
  * The date, time and full Uniform Resource Locators (URLs) of your clicks to, through and from the Site; 
  * Services you search for on the Site, view and/or use; and 
  * Sections of the Site you visit. 

There are companies that provide tools that allow you to visit websites anonymously. While use of these tools may prevent us from providing you with personalized service, you should be aware that this option is available. 

The methods that may be used on the Service to collect Usage Information include: 

  * **Log Information:** Log information is data about your use of the Service, such as IP address, browser type, internet service provider, referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamps, and related data, which is stored in log files.  
  * **Information Collected by Tracking Technologies:** Cookies, web beacons (also known as "tracking pixels"), embedded scripts, location-identifying technologies, voice processing technologies, device fingerprinting, in-app tracking methods, and other tracking technologies now and hereafter developed (“Tracking Technologies”) may be used to collect information about your interactions with the Service or e-mails, including information about your browsing and activity behavior.  

>   * **Cookies  **
> 

> 
> Our Service may use “cookies” which are small text files that are stored on a user’s device to make it easier for you to navigate the Service and enable our servers to recognize your browser. A cookie is a file that identifies you as a unique user, and while it does store personal preferences and user data, a cookie does not identify you by name. We use cookies on our Site to help provide you with a more personalized browsing experience, and to help us better understand and improve our Site and its services. Cookies may remain on your device for extended periods of time.  While you are free to disable cookies on your browser to use our Site, some of our features may not work if cookies are disabled. For example, without cookies, you may not be able to set customized searches, personalized preferences or other customized preferences. 
> 
>   * **Web Beacons (“Tracking Pixels”)  **
> 

> 
> Our Site may also use “Web beacons” to compile aggregate statistics about Site usage. A “Web beacon” is an electronic image, called a single-pixel (1×1) or clear GIF. Web beacons can recognize certain types of information on your computer, such as your cookie number, time and date of a page view, and a description of the page where the Web beacon is placed. We use these Web beacons to tailor our Site to provide better customer service. These Web beacons often work in conjunction with cookies but browsers can be set to refuse cookies or to provide warning whenever cookies are being received. 
> 
>   * **Embedded Scripts  **
> 

> 
> An embedded script is programming code designed to collect information about your interactions with the Service. It is temporarily downloaded onto your device from our web server or a third party with whom we work, is active only while you are connected to the Service, and deleted or deactivated thereafter. 
> 
>   * **Location-identifying Technologies  **
> 

> 
> GPS (global positioning systems) software, geo-filtering, and other location-aware technologies locate (sometimes precisely) you for purposes such as verifying your location and delivering or restricting relevant content based on your location. 
> 
>   * **Voice Processing Technologies.    **
> 

> 
> Voice processing technologies analyze the data collected through the microphone on your device for purposes such as responding to your requests and providing you with relevant content based on your requests. Company does not have access to your actual voice; however, third parties may have access and you should review their policies accordingly. 
> 
>   * **Device Fingerprinting.  **
> 

> 
> Device fingerprinting is the process of analyzing and combining sets of information elements from your device’s browser, such as JavaScript objects and installed fonts, in order to create a “fingerprint” of your device and uniquely identify your device and applications. 
> 
>   * **In-App Tracking Methods.  **
> 

> 
> There are a variety of tracking technologies that may be included in mobile apps, and these are not browser-based like cookies and cannot be controlled by browser settings. Some use device identifier, or other identifiers such as “Ad IDs” to associate app user activity to a particular app and to track user activity across apps. 

Some information about your use of the Service and certain Third Party Services (defined below) may be collected using Tracking Technologies across time and services and used by us and third parties for purposes such as to associate different devices you use, and deliver relevant ads and/or other content to you on the Service and certain Third Party Services. 

For further information on Tracking Technologies and your choices regarding them, please see “Third Party Services, Features, and Devices” and “Your Rights and Choices” below. 

**Information You Provide.  **

We and our Service Providers (defined below) may collect information you provide directly via the Service. For example, we collect information when you access our content, apply for a job through our Site or otherwise communicate or transact with us through the Service.  

The information we collect may include Personal Information. " **Personal Information** " is information that identifies you personally (whether alone or in combination), including without limitation: your name, address, birth date, telephone and fax numbers, email address, credit card information, and communication preferences. Of course, we also collect the information that you choose to provide when you submit a transmission or other materials to the Site. You may always choose not to provide the information we request; however, you may then be unable to take advantage of the features and services we offer on our Site. If you are under 13 years of age, you and your parent must review the section below titled “Policy Regarding Children”, which will govern your provision of personally identifiable information. 

**Information from other Sources.** From time to time we may purchase or otherwise acquire information about you from other sources and add it to our database, including updated address information, customer lists, email address lists, etc.  To the extent we combine such third party sourced information with Personal Information we have collected about you on the Service, we will treat the combined information as Personal Information under this Privacy Policy. We are not responsible for the accuracy of any information provided by third parties or third party policies or practices. 

**HOW WE USE INFORMATION WE COLLECT  **

We understand that your Personal Information is private and confidential. That’s why we want you to know what information we need to offer our Service to you, and how we use that information. We may use information about you for any purposes consistent with our statements under this Privacy Policy or as permitted by applicable law, including to: 

  * Manage our Service; 
  * Respond to your comments, questions, and requests, and provide customer service; 
  * Send you technical notices, updates, security alerts, information regarding changes to our policies, and support and administrative messages; 
  * Prevent and address fraud, breach of policies or terms, and threats or harm;  
  * Monitor and analyse trends, usage, and activities; 
  * Conduct research, including focus groups and surveys;  
  * Improve the Service, the Site or other applications, marketing efforts, products and services;  
  * Send you advertisements and communicate with you regarding our and third party products, services, offers, promotions, rewards and events we think you may be interested in (for information about how to manage these communications and marketing efforts, please see “Your Rights and Choices” below);  
  * Fulfill any other purpose disclosed at the time you provide Personal Information. 

**SHARING OF INFORMATION  **

**Third Party Service Providers.** We may, from time to time, engage agents, vendors, consultants and other service providers (collectively, “Service Providers") in connection with their work on our behalf to provide the Service. For example, we may engage other companies to host, operate and maintain our Site, analyze data, and provide marketing assistance. We may give those Service Providers access to your Personal Information, but only to the extent necessary to provide this assistance. We may also share information about you with third parties for any purposes consistent with our statements under this Privacy Policy or as permitted by applicable law, including as follows: 

  * As required by law or to comply with a subpoena or court order or other legal process, and where required, in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements; 
  * To protect the rights, property, life, health, security and safety of us, the Service or any third party; 
  * In connection with, or during negotiations of, any proposed or actual merger, purchase, sale or any other type of acquisition or business combination of all or any portion of our assets, or transfer of all or a portion of our business to another business; 
  * With our affiliates for internal business purposes; 
  * With our affiliates, business partners, and other third parties for their own business purposes, including direct marketing purposes (California residents and European data subjects have certain rights set forth in “Your California Privacy Rights” and “Your European Privacy Rights” below); 
  * For purposes disclosed at the time you provide Personal Information; and 
  * With your consent or at your direction. 

Although we use reasonable precautions to ensure that our Service Providers protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee that those companies will protect your personal information to the same extent described in this Privacy Policy. 

**Statistical Information.** LAIKA shares some information about its visitors with business partners, sponsors and other third parties; however, that information is statistical in nature, it is aggregated, and does not identify specific individuals. 

**YOUR RIGHTS AND CHOICES  **

**Accessing Your Information.**    

We provide you with an opportunity to access, update, or remove certain account information that you have voluntarily submitted to us through the Service by sending an e-mail to us at [ask_laika@laika.com](mailto:ask_laika@laika.com). We may require additional information from you to allow us to confirm your identity. Please note that we will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. California residents have additional rights set forth in “Your California Privacy Rights” below. 

**Tracking Technologies Generally.**  

Regular cookies may generally be disabled or removed by tools available as part of most commercial browsers, and in some instances blocked in the future by selecting certain settings.  Browsers offer different functionalities and options so you may need to set them separately. With respect to our mobile apps, you can stop all collection of information via an app by uninstalling the app.  Also, you may be able to exercise specific privacy choices, such as enabling or disabling certain location-based services, by adjusting the permissions in your mobile device. 

Please be aware that if you disable or remove Tracking Technologies some parts of the Service may not work and that when you revisit the Service your ability to limit browser-based Tracking Technologies is subject to your browser settings and limitations.  

Your browser settings may allow you to automatically transmit a “Do Not Track” signal to online services you visit.  Note, however, there is no industry consensus as to what site and app operators should do with regard to these signals. Accordingly, we do not monitor or take action with respect to “Do Not Track” signals or other mechanisms.  For more information on “Do Not Track,” visit [http://www.allaboutdnt.com](http://www.allaboutdnt.com/). 

**Analytics and Advertising Tracking Technologies.  **

You may exercise choices regarding the use of cookies from Google Analytics by going to [https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout) or downloading the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on. 

You may exercise choices regarding receipt of Interest-based Advertising by submitting opt outs.  Some of the advertisers and Service Providers that perform advertising-related services for us and our partners may participate in the Digital Advertising Alliance (" **DAA** ") Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising. To learn more about how you can exercise certain choices regarding Interest-based Advertising, visit [http://www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices), and [http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices](http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices) for information on the DAA’s opt out program for mobile apps.  Some of these companies may also be members of the Network Advertising Initiative (“ **NAI** ”). To learn more about the NAI and your opt out options for their members, see [http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/). Please be aware that, even if you are able to opt out of certain kinds of Interest-based Advertising, you may continue to receive other types of ads.  Opting out only means that those selected members should no longer deliver certain Interest-based Advertising to you, but does not mean you will no longer receive any targeted content and/or ads (e.g., from other ad networks). Company is not responsible for effectiveness of, or compliance with, any third-parties’ opt out options or programs or the accuracy of their statements regarding their programs.  

**Online  Communications. ** From time to time, we may send you certain promotional communications (including email messages and push notifications), for purposes such as to keep you apprised of Site developments, to inform you of new offers, and to deliver email newsletters to which you have subscribed. We may use a bulk email service to distribute that information. If you do not wish to receive these communications in the future, you can opt-out at any time by: (i) for e-mails, following the instructions as provided in e-mails to click on the unsubscribe link, or contacting us at [ask_laika@laika.com](mailto:ask_laika@laika.com) with the word UNSUBSCRIBE in the subject field of the e-mail; and (ii) for push notifications or in-app messages, adjusting the permissions in your mobile device.  Please note that your opt-out is limited to the e-mail address or device used and will not affect subsequent subscriptions or, for e-mails, non-promotional communications, such as those about your account, transactions, servicing, or LAIKA’s ongoing business relations. 

**Mailings.** If you supply us with your postal address, you may receive periodic mailings from LAIKA, with information on new products and services, or upcoming events. If you do not wish to receive such mailings, please let us know via e-mail at [ ask_laika@laika.com](mailto:ask_laika@laika.com). 

**Your California Privacy Rights.  **

California’s “Shine the Light” law permits customers in California to request certain details about how certain types of their information are shared with third parties and, in some cases, affiliates, for those third parties’ and affiliates’ own direct marketing purposes. Under the law, a business should either provide California customers certain information upon request or permit California customers to opt in to, or opt out of, this type of sharing. 

LAIKA may share personal information as defined by California’s “Shine the Light” law with third parties and/or affiliates for such third parties’ and affiliates’ own direct marketing purposes. If you are a California resident and wish to obtain information about our compliance with this law, please e-mail us [ask_laika@laika.com](mailto:ask_laika@laika.com) or send us a letter to 6750 NE Bennett Street, Hillsboro OR 97124. Requests must include “California Privacy Rights Request” in the first line of the description and include your name, street address, city, state, and ZIP code. Please note that Company is not required to respond to requests made by means other than through the provided e-mail address or mail address. 

Any California residents under the age of eighteen (18) who have registered to use the Service and posted content or information on the Service, can request that such information be removed from the Service by sending an e-mail to us [ask_laika@laika.com](mailto:ask_laika@laika.com). Requests must state that the user personally posted such content or information and detail where the content or information is posted. We will make reasonable good faith efforts to remove the post from prospective public view. 

**Your European Privacy Rights.**  

If you are a European or Switzerland data subject, you have the right to ask us not to process your Personal Information (or provide it to third parties to process) for marketing purposes or purposes materially different than for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by you. To exercise your right, please e-mail us [ask_laika@laika.com](mailto:ask_laika@laika.com) or send us a letter to 6750 NE Bennett Street, Hillsboro OR 97124. We will try to make the requested changes in our active databases as soon as reasonably practical. 

**THIRD PARTY SERVICES, FEATURES AND DEVICES  **

Our Service contains content from and links to, third party websites, locations, platforms and services operated and owned by third parties (“Third Party Services”). For example, if you click on a third party link, the click may take you from our Site to the website of that other company or person. In addition, our Service contains features that allow you to interact with, connect to, or access our Service through certain Third Party Services and third party devices (“Third Party Features”). Those other website may not have privacy policies or may have privacy policies that are not as protective of your personal information as this Privacy Policy. Remember that third parties may use Tracking Technologies to independently collect information about you and may solicit Personal Information from you. Also, if you use a Third Party Feature, both we and the applicable third party may have access to and use information associated with your use of the Third Party Feature. If you publicly reference our Service on a Third Party Service (e.g., by using a hashtag associated with Company in a tweet or post), we may use your reference on or in connection with our Service.  

Our Service also contains Tracking Technologies operated by third parties. For example, analytics services, such as Google Analytics, may use Tracking Technologies on our Service to help us analyze your use of the Service, compile statistic reports on the Service’s activity, and provide other services relating to Service activity and internet usage. Similarly, ad serving services, advertisers, and other third parties may use Tracking Technologies on our Service and Third Party Services to track your activities across time and services, and tailor ads to you based on your activities, which may include sending you an ad on a Third Party Service or third party device after you have left the Service (“Interest-based Advertising”). 

The information collected and stored by third parties, whether through our Service, a Third Party Service, a Third Party Feature, or a third party device, remains subject to their own policies and practices, including what information they share with us, your choices on their services and devices, and whether they store information in the U.S. or elsewhere. We are not responsible for and make no representations regarding third party policies and practices, and we strongly recommend that you review and understand the privacy policies of the websites you visit and online services you use, whether you visit those websites or access those services directly or through a link from a page on our Site.  To the extent we combine information we receive from third parties with Personal Information we collect directly from you on the Service, we will treat the combined information as Personal Information under this Privacy Policy.  

For further information on Tracking Technologies and your choices regarding them, please see “Information Collected Automatically” above and “Your Rights and Choices” below. 

**POLICY REGARDING CHILDREN  **

**Overview.** We at LAIKA believe it essential that parents are involved in their children’s online experiences. The Children's Online Privacy Protection Act ("COPPA") requires us to inform parents and legal guardians about how we collect, use, and disclose personal information from children less than 13 years of age. This Section describes our practices with respect to information we collect from you, as well as from your child. Under COPPA, we may not, and we do not, condition your child's participation in any LAIKA activity on the provision of more information than is reasonably necessary for your child to participate in that activity. This Section is in addition to the other provisions of this Privacy Policy, which will continue to apply. 

Except as otherwise provided in these Terms, or for purposes of facilitating internal operations of the Service, we do not collect information about you or your child when you use our Service unless you choose to provide information to us. When the Service needs to collect information about a child under 13 years old, COPPA required information and instructions will be provided by the specific Site page that collects information about the child. The Site page will specify exactly what the information will be used for, who will see it, and how long it will be kept. 

There are several exceptions that permit collection of a child's email address without receiving parental consent in advance: 

  * To provide the parents with notice and to seek consent for communications with the child. Note: this may require collection of the parent's email address as well. 
  * To respond to a one time request from a child. 
  * To provide support for internal operations. 
  * To respond more than once to a child's request; i.e., subscription to a newsletter. However, parental consent is required prior to the second communication. 
  * To protect the safety of a child who is participating on the site; i.e., in a chat room. 
  * To protect the site or to respond to law enforcement; i.e., in the case the Site is compromised. 

**Collection of Personally Identifiable Information Collected from Children.** In order to submit drawings or other materials to the Site, and to receive proper credit for such submission, we will directly collect personally identifiable information about you and your child, including (i) your first and last name, your email address, and your date of birth; and (ii) your child's name and date of birth. 

**Parental Consent.** When your child is asked to provide personally identifiable information, we will first collect your (the parent's) email address and use this information to contact you (the parent) by email to notify you that your child wishes to provide personally identifiable information to us, describe the purposes for which the personally identifiable information is collected, and provide you an opportunity to opt-out of the collection of the information. The email will include details on how the parent may (i) provide LAIKA with consent; (ii) prohibit LAIKA from any further contact with the child; or (iii) delete the child's personally identifiable information. You have the option to consent to the collection and use of your child's personally identifiable information without consenting to our disclosure of such information to unaffiliated third parties. 

**Use of Personally Identifiable Information Collected from Children.** When we collect personally identifiable information from children, we will only use that information for the express purpose for which it was collected. 

**Sharing of Personally Identifiable Information Collected from Children.** Except as provided above, we do not share personally identifiable information collected from children with any unaffiliated third parties. 

Note to Parents and Legal Guardians. Please contact LAIKA at any time regarding privacy questions or concerns, or to request to review what personally identifiable information we have collected from a child. Parents may also contact us at any time to request that we delete the personally identifiable information of a child or a parent and/or refuse to permit further collection or use of a child's information. We will take steps to ensure that any person contacting us for a child's information is that child's parent or guardian. If we become aware that we have inadvertently received personally identifiable information from a user under the age of thirteen other than in a legally permissible situation, we will delete the information from our records as soon as we discover it. 

LAIKA, LLC.   
6750 NE Bennett Street, Hillsboro OR 97124   
Attention: LAIKA Legal  
Telephone:[503-615-3344](tel:503-615-3344)   
Fax:[503-615-3345](tel:503-615-3345)   
email:  [laika-legal@laika.com](mailto:ask_laika@laika.com)

**SWEEPSTAKES, CONTESTS AND PROMOTIONS  **

We may offer sweepstakes, contests, surveys, and other promotions (each, a “Promotion”) jointly sponsored or offered by third parties that may require submitting Personal Information. If you voluntarily choose to enter a Promotion, your Personal Information may be disclosed to third parties for administrative purposes and as required by law (e.g., on a winners list). By entering, you agree to the official rules that govern that Promotion, and may, except where prohibited by applicable law, allow the sponsor and/or other parties to use your name, voice and/or likeness in advertising or marketing materials. 

**INTERNATIONAL TRANSFER OF INFORMATION  **

If you choose to provide us with personally identifiable information, LAIKA may transfer that information to its affiliates and subsidiaries or to other third parties, across borders, and from your country or jurisdiction to other countries or jurisdictions around the world. If you are visiting from the European Union or other jurisdictions with laws governing data collection and use that may differ from U.S. law, please note that you are transferring your personally identifiable information to the United States which does not have the same data protection laws as the EU or such other jurisdictions, and by providing your Personal Information you consent to: (1) the use of your Personal Information for the uses identified above in accordance with this Privacy Policy; and (2) the transfer to and from, processing, usage, sharing and storage of your information, including Personal Information, in the United States as indicated above. 

**PRIVACY SHIELD AND DATA TRANSFER   **

LAIKA complies with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of Personal Information from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States, respectively. Company has certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles of notice, choice, accountability for onward transfer, security, data integrity and purpose limitation, access, and recourse, enforcement and liability. For purposes of this Section, LAIKA refers to the following U.S. legal entities: LAIKA, LLC. 

In accordance with our obligations under Privacy Shield, and subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission, we hereby affirm our commitment to subject to the Privacy Shield Principles all Personal Information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland in reliance on Privacy Shield. This means that, in addition to our other obligations under the Privacy Shield Principles, we shall be liable to you for any third party agent to which we transfer your Personal Information and that processes such Personal Information in a manner that violates the Privacy Shield Principles, unless we can demonstrate that we are not responsible for the resulting damages. 

In the event that you have any inquiry, dispute, or claim arising out of or relating to our compliance with Privacy Shield, please e-mail us at  [ask_laika@laika.com](mailto:ask_laika@laika.com) or send us a letter to 6750 NE Bennett Street, Hillsboro OR 97124. If we are unable to resolve your complaint directly, you may submit your complaint at no cost to you to JAMS at  [https://www.jamsadr.com/file-an-eu-us-privacy-shield-or-safe-harbor-claim](https://www.jamsadr.com/file-an-eu-us-privacy-shield-or-safe-harbor-claim). In the event there are residual complaints that have not been resolved by JAMS, or any other means, you may seek a non-monetary remedy through binding arbitration to be provided to you in accordance with the Privacy Shield Principles. 

To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, and to view Company’s certification, please visit  [https://www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/). 

**HOW WE PROTECT YOUR INFORMATION  **

We understand that you are providing personal information to us. While we have gone to great lengths to describe what it is that we collect and how we use it, we would also like you to know how we protect your information. It is our intention to treat your account information with the highest level of care. Along those lines, we have implemented industry standard firewall protection and password protected all of the databases that contain your information. Although we use reasonable precautions to keep your personal information secure, we cannot be responsible for any breach of security or for the actions of any third parties. Further, our Privacy Policy does not extend to anything that is inherent in the operation of the Internet, and therefore beyond our control. 

**MISCELLANEOUS  **

**Disputes regarding use of Personal Information.** All disputes regarding our use of your personal information and/or the terms of this Privacy Policy will be resolved as more specifically provided in our Site’s Terms of Use. 

**Changes to this Privacy Policy.** We reserve the right at our discretion to make changes to this Privacy Policy at any time. We will undertake reasonable efforts to notify you of material changes to this statement by providing notice on our Site. Please review this page periodically for changes. 

**Questions.** If you at any time have questions about this Privacy Policy, please send your question via email to [laika-legal@laika.com](mailto:laika-legal@laika.com) or send via first class mail to 6750 NE Bennett Street, Hillsboro OR 97124.
